今夜，我指点江山
Tonight, I point at some fields,
理查德在角落里东张西望
Richard minces round a corner,
詹姆斯讲述他的理想夜生活
and James describes his ideal night in.
呕吐物和口水，以及其它各种排泄物
Vomit and sputum,and other bodily secretions.
遗忘天下，个人翻译，如有错误，万望海涵
制作：遗忘天下 校订：遗忘天下 上传：遗忘天下  QQ号：529098103 欢迎车迷同学加好友
英文字幕来源MemoryOnSmells http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
大家好，晚上好。谢谢大家。非常感谢
Hello, good evening.Thank you so much. Thank you.
谢谢。好的。我们开始
Thank you. Now, we begin,
今晚我们从揽胜运动版开始说起
we begin with the Range Rover Sport.
经历了八年的时光，揽胜运动版即将走到尽头
After eight years,it's gone out of production.
路虎将不再生产该款车型
They are not going to make any more.
这是一件好事
And this is a good thing,
因为这车一直有个大问题
because there's always been one major problem with it,
理查德哈蒙德接下来会向各位解释其中缘由
as Richard Hammond shall now explain.
就是这款车了，即将走下历史舞台的路虎揽胜运动版
Here we are, then. The soon-to-be deceased Range Rover Sport.
这车身上可能有很多你不喜欢的因素
There are many things you might object to about this car.
但最大的问题总是显而易见的
But the biggest problem has always been very simple.
就是它的名字 - 揽胜运动版
It's the badge - Range Rover Sport.
首先，在这车的外表之下实际是一台路虎发现的底盘
First of all, underneath this is the chassis of a Land Rover Discovery
所以这货不是真正的揽胜
so it's not a Range Rover,
并且因为用的是发现的底盘
and because it's the chassis of a Land Rover Discovery,
这车的体重接近3吨
it weighs nearly three tonnes.
所以它也不怎么运动
So it's not sporty either.
它成功的忽悠了许多不知实情的
Its success hinged on appealing to people who didn't know that,
或知道真相的傻富帅
or indeed, anything.
实际上，这车的买主通常只有两类人 - 球星
Basically, this car was only bought by two types of people - footballers
以及球星们的老婆
and people who were married to footballers.
所以这车的老家在这里
And the Sport's stamping ground is this place.
位于柴郡的英超球员居住区威尔姆斯洛
The Premier League ghetto of Wilmslow in Cheshire.
乔治亚式暴发户电动大门
Genuine Georgian electric gates right there.
这里也是。那里也是
And there. And there.
乔治亚式暴发户私人监控摄像头
Georgian security cameras.
整齐的草坪，很适合私家烧烤
Manicured lawns, very popular for spit-roast barbecues.
显然，这里的阔佬们会比其它郡的居民
Apparently, they drink more champagne per head here
消耗更多的香槟酒
than in any other county.
真富有
Class.
威尔姆斯洛的富人们会怀念这款车
The people of Wilmslow are going to miss this car,
不过在他们为此伤心之前
but before they start weeping onto their marble breakfast bars,
我有个好消息要告诉他们
I have some good news.
因为路虎推出了新款换代车型
Because now there is a new one.
新车起售价5W英镑（46.8万人民币），比现款揽胜更便宜
With prices starting at £50,000, it's cheaper than a proper Range Rover
并且有七个座椅，所以更为实用
and because it's available with seven seats, it's more practical, as well.
但就像我开始时说的那样
But like I said at the beginning,
老款揽胜运动版有些名不副实
the old Range Rover Sport was a bit of a fraud.
新的问题同样如此，这车是否是一辆真正的揽胜
The question must be,is this one really a Range Rover
并且像它名字一样真的很运动呢？
and is it a Sport?
让我们开始第一项挑战
Let's start with that first bit.
不论装备有多豪华奢侈，决定这车是否担得起揽胜这块金字招牌的标准
No matter how much wood and leather it's fitted with, the mark
就在于它能不能搞定这些严酷的地形
of a real Range Rover is being able to tackle this sort of stuff.
现在是关键，来了
Important work being done,coming through.
首先你要知道
Well, the first thing you need to know
在这辆揽胜的外表之下不再是一辆路虎发现
is that this is not a Discovery in a Range Rover frock.
它有着货真价实的揽胜底盘
It has the proper Range Rover chassis
以及和揽胜一样的地形回馈系统
and the same terrain response system, as well.
这些系统实时探测你驶过的路面情况
This analyses the ground you're driving over
同时自动地调整悬挂阻尼，变速箱响应
and automatically adjusts the suspension, gearbox,
刹车以及引擎输出功率
brakes and engine output to suit.
来了、来了，这坡几乎就是垂直的悬崖！
Big, big, almost vertical hill now!
坡度非常陡，非常陡，很泥泞
Very steep, very steep, very muddy.
这真是...这才叫爬坡
That is... that is a climb.
干的不错，小家伙
Well done, you.
除了地形回馈系统，还有个控制防倾杆的行车电脑
Besides the terrain response,there's also a computer
用来调整轮胎对地面的附着力
that disconnects the anti-roll bars to increase wheel articulation.
轻松搞定
We're over.
我想说，我刚刚驶过一个大的交叉驼峰
I mean, that was a big old cross-axling hump to get over.
可我甚至都没有注意到这一点！
It didn't even notice!
这车还有更多本事
And there's more.
啊！积水
Ah! Water.
很好。是时候使用秘密武器了
Good. Gives me a chance to play with something else I have on board
秘密武器就是...
and that is...
声纳。大吃一惊吧！
sonar. Kid you not!
声纳装置就安装在后视镜里面
Sonar transmitters and receivers in the door mirrors
实时探测水的深度
measure the depth of the water.
在水位过高时会发出警报
It will make a big noise if it's getting too deep.
现在的水深不需要担心，没问题
It's not worried, not worried.
我感觉就像驾驶着一间豪华总统套房驶过这片泥地
I feel like I'm driving a luxury hotel room through a swamp.
酷
Cool.
哦嚯！真陡！
Oh-ho! That's steep!
假装什么都没发生过...
Just pretty much like it never...
那里，我想我已经修好了
There, I think I've repaired that.
多多少少还有点。就这样了
More or less. That's how it was.
很好
Good.
所以，总结一下
So, there we are.
这辆车，在识货的人手上，是很好的越野利器
This car, in the right hands,is very good off-road.
但是现在，我们要继续对它进行其他测试
And now, we must move on,
针对这车标榜的运动特性
to this bit of the badge.
欢迎来到多宁顿公园赛道（曾经的F1赛道）
Welcome to Donington Park racetrack,
如果这货真像路虎官方声称的那么运动
and if the Sport is as sporty as Land Rover claims,
那它在这里的表现应该会很不错
it should put on a good show here.
如今这车有V6和V8两款柴油引擎可供选择
Now, you can get these with a V6 or a V8 diesel.
我现在驾驶的这款车是503马力的V8车型
The one I'm in is the supercharged petrol V8 with 503-brake horsepower,
这就是我要驾驭的动力
so that is the power taken care of.
因为这车采用了全新的揽胜全铝合金底盘
And because it's built on the brand-new all-aluminium chassis of the proper Range Rover,
所以它比老款揽胜运动版轻了半吨
it's getting on for half a tonne lighter than the old Sport.
那个弯，出弯，随后而来的动力汹涌澎湃！
That turn, lift, and then it comes around and then bang!
503匹的强劲四驱动力让你行驶如飞！
503-braked all four wheels and off you go!
在减轻重量的同时
And as well as the weight loss,
电子控制的防侧倾杆实时对抗车身的弯道倾斜
the computer-controlled suspension fights body roll,
并且这车还有一套类似宝马M5的后轮主动差速器
and there's an active rear diff like you'd get on a BMW M5.
它还有一套被称作扭矩矢量控制的系统
It also has something called torque vectoring,
这是一套用来决定每个车轮何时何地分配多少动力的系统
which dictates how much power is sent to each of the wheels and when.
我的意思是，这些东西都是超级跑车才会用到的玩意
I mean, that is supercar stuff.
就像你在迈凯轮MP-12C上能看到的东西
That's what you get on the McLaren 12C road car.
更让我惊叹的是
What's staggering me right now
把这车开到这条赛道上
is that hurling this car around this racetrack,
它感觉并不像是我在逼它做一件它不愿意的事情
it doesn't feel like I'm asking it to do anything it doesn't want to do.
这感觉就像是坐在家中的沙发上一样
It feels at home.
简而言之，在这条赛道上，它很出色。但究竟有多出色？
All in all, on a track,it's good. But how good?
好的，为了找出确切答案
Well, to find out,
我们必须，就像通常一样，请出我们活泼可爱的圈养车手来做测试
we must, as ever, call on the help of the world's chattiest racing driver.
今天，Stig要驾驶一辆mini cooper GP
Today, The Stig is in a Mini John Cooper Works GP,
你能买到的全球最NB的掀背小车
one of the most hardcore hot-hatches you can buy.
现在，他要用这辆mini做一圈成绩
And now, he's going to use it to set a lap time.
准备好了之后...走你！
When you're ready... go!
现在，让我们看看
Now, let's find out
这个成绩能不能被这辆又大又重的四驱车给击败
if that can be beaten by the big, bulky four by four.
为了监督程序按规定执行，我坐上了副驾
And to oversee proceedings,I shall ride shotgun.
好处在于
The beauty of this is,
这家伙不知道上一款车叫什么名字，也不知道这款车是怎么回事
he has no idea what that last car was called, no idea what he's in now.
毫不关心。没有偏见，如你所见
Doesn't care. No bias, you see.
他所能做的就是尽可能的开快
All he can do is try and go as fast as he can.
我们出发了！
And we're off!
进入第一弯，没有带刹车
Head towards the first corner, not braking at all for the first corner.
噢，真是非常，非常的快！
Oh, that's very,very quick down there!
这速度我都快失禁了
Some wee might have come out there.
哇噢！完美刹车。很好
Whoa! Brakes work. That's good.
不用担心他被甩出去
I'm not worried about putting him off
因为这点打滑声对他来说就像鸭叫一样。毫不足虑
because this is just like a quacking noise for him. It's irrelevant.
现在是很关键的时刻
It's worth remembering about now
这毕竟还是一辆很大、很重的车
that this is still a very big, heavy car.
它的重量比最重的奔驰S级还要大
It weighs more than the heaviest Mercedes S-class.
但在Stig的极限驾驭下，这车依旧尽在掌握
But even at Stig speed, the Sport seemed to have everything in order.
理论上我们现在的车身姿态应该和比萨斜塔有得一拼
We should be The Leaning Tower of Range Rover Sport right now,
但是我们没有。这真是太神奇了！
but somehow we're not.It's fantastic!
刚刚过去一分钟
We just crossed over a minute.
这磨胎声是磨胎史上
That's the longest protracted tyre squeal
最长的磨胎声
in the history of tyres and squealing.
噢，这真是...我的天，简直和飞一样
Oh, that is... My, that was flying.
S弯！真快
Chicane! That is fast.
最后的大直道
And on to the final straight.
129.8秒是我们的目标
129.8 to beat.
129.5秒。没错
129.5. There it is.
所以，路虎开了这么多年的空头支票
So, after years of writing cheques it can't cash,
如今这款车终于赢得了实至名归的揽胜运动版称号
this car has finally earned the right to be called the Range Rover Sport.
超越老款一大截。真的很不错。是的
Massively better than the old one.Massively better. Yeah.
终于，它能配得上这个运动版的称号了
And definitely worthy now of the Range Rover Sport badge,
但我更喜欢比较大的老款揽胜
but I'd still prefer to have the big proper Range Rover.
不，如果你买了大号的揽胜，你会很长时间后悔自己
No, because if you buy the big one,you'll spend half your time
没有买新运动版并且还节省了2万块
wishing you'd saved 20 grand and bought the Sport.
不，你这么看，关键在于
No, because you see, the thing is,
老款揽胜有分体式后备箱门
the proper Range Rover has a split tailgate,
这是所有揽胜都应该有的配置。看。那货就没有这个高科技
which all Range Rovers should have.Look. That one doesn't have this.
确实没有，但是新运动版比老款更好看
No, but the Range Rover Sport is better looking.
驾驶感更好，并且还有七个座位
It's better to drive,and you can get it with seven seats.
是的，但是当我带着我的爱犬出门遛弯的时候，知道吗
Yes, but when I take my dogs for a walk, OK,
它们窜出去之后我看着后门
they leap out and I look at that
同时想到，“是的！你看，我能这么优雅的坐着”
and think, "Yes! You know what,I'll have a nice sit down."
所以你所谓的遛狗就是坐着？没错，我喜欢坐着
So your walks are spent sitting down?Yeah, I like sitting down.
什么，你多花2万镑（18.7万人民币）就为了那个分体式后备箱门？
What, so you'd spend £20,000 basically on a bench?
既然如此你为什么不买辆新运动版
Why wouldn't you buy the Sport
同时去加油站的便利店花1英镑买个便宜的折叠椅子？
and one of those folding chairs from a petrol station for a quid?
但它不是折叠门
But it isn't just the bench.
这辆更大，而且正如我们所知道的一样，更大通常就代表着更好
This is bigger, and bigger, as we know, is always better than smaller.
好吧，也不是所有时候都更好，比如...
Well, not always, not in...
比如擦伤，就不是
Not in bruises, it's not.
擦伤确实不是。但有奖证券呢
Not bruises, no. Premium Bond wins.
心脏病
Heart attacks.
呃...
Erm...
烟火表演
Fireworks.
喜出望外的消费账单
Unexpected bills.
女同学们，你们谁能想出有什么东西是
Ladies, can you think of anything which is better
大比小更好的？（邪恶的杰瑞米 - -#）
when it's bigger than smaller?
好的，现在是新闻环节。几个星期以前
Now, the news.And a couple of weeks ago,
在录制完节目返回的时候，我行驶在A3公路上
on the way back from the show,going along the A3,
一个前方的交通事故把我堵在路上一个半小时
I was held up for an hour and a half by an accident.
当我拼死拼活挤到车龙的前面去时
When I eventually got to the front of the queue,
我看见了事故车满地的残渣碎片
expecting a scene of devastation,
一辆菲亚特500的保险杠半挂在车的一端
I found a Fiat 500 with the bumper hanging off at one end...
噢，不！两、三条道路都被封闭了
Oh, no!Two of the three lanes closed,
然后许多穿制服的人就出现在了现场
and then just a load of people in uniforms sort of milling about.
这些穿制服的人，詹姆斯，让我猜猜
These people in uniform,James, let me guess,
他们是不是叫做“高速公路交通执法局事故处理员”？
were they by any chance Highway Agency Traffic Enforcement Officers?
啊哈，是的。我就知道他们是。我们以前谈到过他们
Ah, yes. I knew they would be. We've spoken about these people before
并且我们今天又要谈到他们
and I think we should speak about them again
因为他们任职于高速公路管理处
because they were employed by the Highways Agency
以保持高速路的通畅，但是他们经常干的事情就是封闭高速路。没错
to keep the roads open, and all they ever do is shut them. Yeah.
他们到了现场做的第一件事就是“好的，必须马上封路”
As soon as they get their first job,"Right, must close the road."
“后视镜掉了？封路”
"Dislodged door mirror?Close the road."
“有孩子晕车了？封路”
"Child a bit carsick?Close the road."
“有人报告说他的颈部扭伤了？封路，绝对没错”
"Someone says they've got whiplash?Close the road. It's serious."
顺便补充一句，说颈部扭伤的人不是真的受伤了，他们其实就是诈骗保险金而已
Whiplash, by the way,is not a serious injury,it's insurance fraud.
这就是他们干的事，并且这些行为需要被禁止
And that's all they do and they've got to be stopped.
我认为他们只能在以下情况时封路
I think they should only be allowed to close the road
那就是用一个词就能描述他所遇到的事故
if certain words are being used to describe the incident.
“地狱”“火山爆发”“世界末日”
"Inferno", "crater", "apocalyptic."
“日本沉没”是的
"Felt in Japan." Yes.
“无头女尸”没错，没错
"Can't find the head." Yes, yes.
如果交通部在报告上这么说
If Sally Traffic says that on the traffic report,
“找不到那人的脑袋了”那你们就可以封路了
"Can't find the head", then you can think about closing the road.
但你仍然需要征得某人的同意才能执行、而那人正是我
But you still have to ring somebody for permission and that is me.
我永远不会批准他们这么干
I'd basically never give them permission.
我只会告诉他们，他们的工作就是清理事故垃圾。没错
I would remind them that their job is to clear up litter. Yes.
这就是他们该干的，通过你的描述，我觉得听起来他们更像是魔法世界的小精灵
They are, as you once described,they're basically Wombles.
是的，这是份不错的工作，他们应该珍惜所得到的一切
Yes, it's a lovely job and they should appreciate what they've got.
这很有意思。他们能在地底工作，地面工作
It's fun. They can work underground, overground.
他们能把找到的东西变成神奇的工具。是的，他们有这本事
They could make good use of the things they find. Yes, they could.
就像传说中那样。多么幸运
Things that everyday folk just leave behind. What an opportunity.
我觉得应该把他们打扮成小精灵那样
I think we should dress them up like actual Wombles.
来吧，有谁想在马路边看看小精灵长啥样？
Come on, who wouldn't want to see a Womble by the side of the road?
我不敢想象我被小精灵拦下来是种什么感觉
I wouldn't mind being stopped by a Womble
这也对各位的人身安全有益，因为没人会忍心开车压过一个小精灵，不是吗？
and it would be good for your own safety because nobody would want to run over a Womble, would they?
你会很小心驾驶的。你会伤心欲绝！
You'd be careful.You'd be heartbroken!
他们也不需要穿制服
They wouldn't need hi-vis.
好的，再聊聊可爱的英国皇家邮政局，就像我们知道的那样，他们经常发行纪念邮票
Now, the Royal Mail, as we know,often issues commemorative stamps.
把一些东西印上去，例如一只啄木鸟，一顶帽子或者一种疾病
They pick on a subject like woodpeckers or hats or diseases.
疾病？！不管怎样，他们最近又打算发行一套邮票
Diseases?! Anyway, they've decided to do a range of stamps
基于经典的英国车型
based on classic British motoring cars.
我找到一些他们试做的样本
I've got some of the ones they've done for you here.
这是莲花精灵。当然这不是邮票的实际尺寸
There's the Lotus Esprit. This isn't the actual size of the stamp.
我刚才还在猜！这只是实物模型
I did wonder! This is a mock-up.
他们印了莲花精灵和阿斯顿马丁DB5
They've got the Lotus Esprit and they've got the Aston Martin DB5
如果你不希望你的信件抵达目的地，那就贴张MG的邮票
and if you don't want your letter to get there, the MG.
噢，天啊，看看这货，多么忧郁的样子
Oh, God, look at that, dismal.
福特英格兰警车。现在它是福特安格利亚（拉丁语英格兰的意思）
The Ford Anglia police car.Now that is a Ford Anglia.
这是我做车评以来遇见过最丑的车，多少年了，25年？80，80年
The scariest thing I've ever done in how many years have been testing cars, 25 years? 80.80 years.
80年了，被吓的大吃了一惊
In 80 years, was doing an emergency stop in one of those.
我老爸在这玩意里失去了他的膝盖骨
My dad lost his kneecaps in one of those.
我说的失去膝盖骨不是这样的，“它们在哪？”它们在车座下面
I don't mean lost them,like, "Where are they?" They'll be under the seat.
他撞车并且被手术切除了膝盖骨
He crashed it and they had to take his kneecaps out,
就在驾驶福特安格利亚的时候。现在他们居然把它印在邮票上
after crashing a Ford Anglia.And now they've put it on a stamp.
下面还有更糟糕的英国车，是吧？
That's more dreadful heritage Britain nonsense, isn't it?
接下来会更糟，看看这辆！这是张印有射手的邮票
It gets worse, look at that one! That is The Archers as a postage stamp.
他们干嘛不印点现代的汽车上去？
Why don't they put something modern on it?
你能印一辆迈凯轮或者一辆宾利慕尚上去
You could put the McLaren or the Bentley Mulsanne on it,
那样邮票会变的很漂亮
that would be fantastic on a stamp.
我是说，就像法国人不会在邮票上印一个骑着自行车的老家伙
I mean, the French wouldn't do a stamp that had an old bloke
或者一件画满洋葱的条纹T恤衫，对吧？
on a bicycle and a stripy T-shirt with some onions, would they?
我说的就和这一样！
That's what that is!
德国人不会在邮票上印一辆半履带装甲车停在华沙城外
The Germans wouldn't do a stamp with a half-track just outside Warsaw.
很传神。不会的，他们确实不会这么干
Exactly. No, they really wouldn't.
不，杰瑞米，显然，他们不会那么干
No, Jeremy, definitely,they wouldn't do that.
他们不会，是吗？
They wouldn't, would they?
管它的，随便了，让我们继续下一个话题
No, anyway, let's move on.
马自达和阿尔法罗密欧宣称他们即将
Now Mazda and Alfa Romeo have announced they're going to do
展开一个小型运动车型的合作开发项目
a joint project to make a small sports car.
马自达给新车取名MX5
Mazda will call theirs the MX5,
阿尔法则取名蜘蛛
Alfa will call theirs the Spider.
问题在于，阿尔法罗密欧曾经干过类似的事情
The trouble is, Alfa Romeo once did this in the past.
他们和日产合作，记得吗？是的
They teamed up with Nissan,remember this? Yes.
他们和日产合作之后，当时我们就想，这是个多棒的主意啊
They teamed up with Nissan and we thought, what a great plan.
阿尔法负责外观设计和引擎部分，尼桑负责车身制造
Alfa does the styling and the engine and then Nissan builds it.
但他们和我们想的恰好相反。是的，他们就是反着来的
But they did it the other way around. Yeah, they did.
那是个史上最愚蠢的决定
It was the stupidest decision in history.
这就是最终的产物，女士们先生们。神车阿纳
This is what we got,ladies and gentlemen. The Arna.
噢，老天
Oh, dear.
设计出自日产之手，车身制造由阿尔法罗密欧负责
Style by Nissan,built by Alfa Romeo.
这就像是彼得·克劳奇和阿比·克兰茜的结合一样
It's a bit like going to Peter Crouch and Abbey Clancy and saying,
“好的，阿比，你去吹黑哨，彼得，你来设计比基尼”
"Right, Abbey, you take the penalty and Peter, you model bikinis."
就是那么愚蠢。没有比这更糟的了
It's that idiotic.They couldn't be more wrong.
所以这回的MX5/蜘蛛，一定要保证马自达来制造
So for this MX5/Spider, job one,make sure Mazda build it.
那是必须的。马自达负责制造车身
That's essential.Mazda do the building.
阿尔法负责设计外观，以及引擎？
Alfa do the styling, engine?
是的、是的、是的。阿尔法做引擎和设计
Yeah, yeah, yeah.Alfa do the engine and the styling,
但是焊接，组装，上螺丝这些活，必须马自达来做
but welding, soldering, doing up the bolts, that's Mazda's job.
我很期待这台阿尔法马自达的合作产物
I really do want to see this Alfa Mazda.
我想这辆结合产物
I think an MX5 Spider joint-venture,
会很不错
that could be brilliant.
接下来我要说一个很重要的话题
Now I want to move it onto something really important.
几个月前市中心有些骚动
A few months ago there was a bit of a brouhaha about town centres
在经济下滑的这个时期，许多商店都关门了
in Britain dying,all the shops closing down.
我们被建议讲一讲这个话题是因为
And we suggested on this show that this is because
现在市中心不允许停车
you aren't really allowed to park anywhere in a town centre,
所以人们都去郊外购物中心买东西，就因为那里能停车
so people go to out-of-town shopping centres, where you can park.
我们曾声明老百姓需要更宽松的停车法令
We said they needed to relax the parking arrangements.
好的，现在我们有了一个强大的盟友了。是吗？难道是奥巴马？
Well, we have a powerful ally.Do we? Is it Barack Obama?
不，不是奥巴马。达斯·维德？（星战黑武士）
No, not Barack Obama. Darth Vader?
不，埃里克·皮克斯。不错啊
No, Eric Pickles. Brilliant.
谁是埃里克·皮克斯。我没听说过。你知道他是谁吗？
Who's Eric Pickles. I've no idea.Do you not know who he is?
好的，他不是黑武士，对吧？
Well, he's not Darth Vader, is he?
埃里克·皮克斯，我能画出他长啥样
Eric Pickles,I can actually draw him.
他有一张很小的脸蛋，非常小
Cos he's got an incredibly small face, he's got a small face
但是他的头却非常大
and then he's got really quite a big head.
所以他实际上就像这样。
So he actually looks like that.
他不是这样的吧。他是的
He doesn't look like that. He does.
让我们看看他真实的照片
Put a proper picture of him on the screen.
噢，天啊，他真的长得就像你画的那样。
Oh, God, he looks like that.He does look like that.
真是太震惊了。多么意外的长相。看啊
That's amazing. What a fabulous arrangement. Look at that.
你能画出他来，真的很简单
You can draw him,it's really quite good.
你能在你的拇指上画出埃里克·皮克斯
You can have your own personal Eric Pickles on your thumb.
哇噢！这是埃里克·皮克斯！
Wow! It's Eric Pickles!
真厉害
That's brilliant.
我喜欢他的脸。这是副不错的长相
I like his face. That's a good face.
画得好。
Excellent facework.
不论如何，埃里克说过了，他是政府官员
Anyway, Eric has said, OK,and he is a government minister,
他说人们应该被允许在单黄线或者双黄线的地方
he said that you should be allowed to stop on a single yellow
临时停车几分钟，如果只是进商店
or a double yellow linejust for a few minutes,
买点牛奶之类的事情
while you pop into a shop to get a pint of milk.
这听起来像是大多人的共识
That sounds like perfectly good common sense.
“我只是买点东西，几分钟而已”等等，虽然如此
"I'm just popping in to the shop,out in a minute." Hang on, though.
但这是BBC的节目，所以我们不要忘了，我们要保证节目的
This is the BBC, let's not forget，so in the interests of balance
公正性和合理性，我要考虑一下这条提议的合理性
and impartiality, I will think of why that isn't a good idea.
这确实是条不错的建议
It's a great idea.
所以就这么愉快的决定了，我们解决了所有的问题，我们在此表明
So there we are, we've addressed all the problems and we can say,
埃里克·皮克斯先生，赶快通过这项法案
Mr Pickles,implement it straight away
不然我们就要把车停到你的脸上去了
or we shall park on your substantial face.
公正地讲，你能在他脸上停十辆车
To be fair, you could get about ten cars on there.
如果你细看，他的下巴就像个环状交岔路
If you look, he's got a mini-roundabout on his chin.
我喜欢埃里克·皮克斯的名字。听起来不错！
I like the sound of Eric Pickles.He sounds brilliant!
他说话挺中听而且名字也不错
He talks good sense and he's called Eric Pickles.
我觉得应该把他请到我们节目来开一次廉价车
I think we should have him on the show in the Reasonably-Priced Car,
但是我又想到一个好主意
but here's the spin,here's the trick.
我们告诉他节目的廉价车是艾瑞欧原子
We tell him the reasonably-priced car is an Ariel Atom,
因为我开那车脸就像剥香蕉皮一样
because I've got a wobbly face that goes a bit like that.
想象一下他开那车会啥样！可能会整个脸都翻过来
Imagine what his face would be like!It could go inside out entirely.
太惊人了。谁想看看埃里克·皮克斯在我们节目里的样子？
Amazing. Who here thinks we should get Eric Pickles on the show?
来吧，皮克斯老兄！来Top Gear。我们希望你过来
Come on, Eric! Please come on Top Gear. We want you.
继续，许多汽车制造商都有这样的造车理念，
Moving on, a lot of carmakers have got it into their heads
肯花30万欧元买辆车的人一定是想有一辆两座的
that anyone who spends £300,000 plus on a car will want only two seats
并且能达到惊人极速的超级跑车
and an absolutely enormous top speed.
举个例子，就像兰博基尼LP-700这样
The Lamborghini Aventador,for example.
这么做是不错，但如果你是一个对速度不怎么感兴趣
And that's great, but what if you're not really interested in speed
同时还想要比这更多座位的购车客户呢？好吧，瞧瞧这个大家伙怎么样？
and you want more than two seats?Well, how about this?
这是辆被期待已久的伦敦双层公交换代车型
It is the long-awaited replacement for the Routemaster.
造价33万英镑（309万人民币）
It costs £330,000 and it's known,
毫无悬念，这就是NBFL，全称：伦敦新型公交车
rather unimaginatively,as the NBFL, the new bus for London.
但它可以当作私家车来用吗，我在想？
But could it be used as a private car, I wonder?
这车能否，实际上，成为一辆NCFS，萨默塞特郡（英格兰西南部农牧区）新型公交车？
Could this, in fact, be the NCFS,the new car for Somerset?
好的，就是这里，正如你们注意到的一样
So, here we are and the first problem you notice
作为新一代伦敦巴士，它有点过于复杂了
with the new London bus is that it's a bit complicated.
所以你不能坐进去马上把它开走
So you can't just get in it and go.
灭火系统压力正常
Fire system pressure OK.'
启动开关。好的。我们出发
Ignition system. Right. Here we go.
靠
Cock.
轮胎气压正常。等等！
Tyre system pressure OK.' Hang on!
轮胎气压正常。噢，闭嘴
Tyre system pressure OK.Oh, bollocks.
最终，当我把所有开关都试过一遍之后
Eventually, though,if you press absolutely everything
这车总算能动了
it will actually start and set off.
看吧！看看这霸气的方向盘。
Look at me!Look at my big steering wheel.
抱歉！
Sorry!
但是这车怎么能当成家用车？
But how does it get on as a car?
好吧、实话实说，这车太宽了
Well, if I'm honest,it is quite wide.
而且，没错，高度也是个问题
And, yeah, all right, very occasionally the height is an issue.
我勒个去！
Cocking Nora!
虽然它有35英尺长（10.7米），但是它驾驶起来很轻松
But even though it's 35 feet long,it's not hard to drive at all.
方向盘很轻而且很精准
The steering is light and quite direct.
它缺乏法拉利458身上的那种干脆的感觉
It lacks the crispness that you find in, say, the Ferrari 458
但这不是坏事
but it's not bad.
更值得一提的是，不像大多数同价位的车型，
What's more, unlike most cars in a similar price bracket,
这车是完完全全的英国本土货
it's extremely home-grown.
这车不是在英国贴牌组装那么简单
It's not something that's just been badged up over here.
它的所有零部件都是英国本土制造。底盘，车身，玻璃。
It's all made in Britain. The chassis, the bodywork, the glass.
生产它的工人也全都是英国人，它促进了英国制造业的发展
It keeps British people employed,it promotes British skill,
它展现了大英帝国的高端制造工艺。这是条死路。靠！
it advertises workmanship.This is a dead-end. Cock!
我该怎么办...？刚才开进来的时候
How did I do...?It didn't say dead-end
路口没标明这是死胡同
at the beginning of the road.
这是个测试机动性的好地方
This, then, would be a good place to test manoeuvrability.'
好的，我能直接开到那因为我就在巴士的前面
Right, I can go right up to that because I'm right at the front of the bus.
倒车吸引了大批围观群众
This did attract a crowd.
但如果你在一辆兰博基尼里尝试三点倒车
But if you try doing a three-point turn in a Lamborghini,
你同样也会受到围观
you get a crowd, as well.
轮胎气压正常。噢，天啊
Tyre system pressure OK.' Oh, God.
你能帮我看看车尾吗？
Can you look at the back for me?
你能帮我检查一下我是不是撞到了建筑物？
Can you check I don't knock a building over?
这就像是维多利亚时代的英国
It's like Victorian Britain.
我雇用了一些童工帮我做事
I've employed some children to do something useful.
唯一的区别就是他们把这车当成了公交车
The only difference is that people do tend to mistake this for a bus.
当心你的狗！..都挤上了车
Mind the dog! '..and get on it.
喂！
Oi!
我的天！下去，你们这群麻烦的，瞎胡闹的小屁孩。下去，下去！快下车。
God above! Get off, you pesky,meddling kids. Off, off! Off, off.
不要掏出手机，不要拍照。下来，下来，下来，下来
No mobile phones, no pressing the button. Off, off, off, off.
回到车里
Stay of the bus.
我把自己关在驾驶室外面了。我把自己关在门外了
I've locked myself out.I've locked myself out of the bus.
用一把老虎钳暴力解决了该问题之后
Having sorted out the problem with pliers,
我直接撞上了一辆大众甲壳虫。咿-咿-咿！
I immediately crashed into a Volkswagen Beetle.' Yi-yi-yi!
之后我又差点撞上一座桥
And then I nearly hit a bridge.'
4.4米？我的车身高度有4.42米！
4.4? We're 4.42! Ah!
老天，真是惊心动魄啊
God, this is exhausting.
幸运的是随着回到大路上
But with the road ahead mercifully free of traffic,
我有机会给大家介绍这辆车都有些什么高科技
there was time to talk about some of the bus's high-tech features.
这是一辆混合动力车
It's a hybrid bus, this.
它有一台柴油引擎和一台电动机
It has a diesel engine and it has an electric motor.
电动机是驱动车辆的主角
The electric motor always drives the wheels.
柴油引擎只是用来给电机发电
The diesel engine generates electricity for the batteries.
所以这辆车和菲斯克·卡玛一个原理
So it is actually like a Fisker Karma.
0-60英里加速时间没有给出
The 0-60 time is not quoted.
因为它开不到60英里的时速
Primarily because it won't do 60.
但它能每秒加速1米。这很不错
But it will accelerate at one metre per second. And that's good.
这意味着上面的乘客不会因为急加速而摔下来
That means people standing up won't fall over.
车身外观如何？
So what about the styling?
它的外观是由设计伦敦奥运会主火炬
Well, it was created by the same people
的同一帮人所操刀的
who did the amazing Olympic cauldron.
这帮人同时也设计了这辆车
And they've done another great job on this.
从背后看，它的长相就像是The Human League乐队的菲尔奥克利的发型
（The Human League是1977年成立的英国流行乐队，菲尔奥克利是乐队主唱之一）
From the back, it looks like Phil Oakey's haircut,out of The Human League.
没错，它确实像个大盒子
All right, it is quite boxy.
但这是因为它是辆巴士
But that's because it's a bus.
当你走进车内有一点变得很明显
A point that becomes obvious when you step inside.
在它的使用寿命期内，它的客运量估计超过400万人次
Over its lifetime, it's reckoned that about four million people
所以它有些关键的设计用来对付这些问题
will get on and off it so it is a bit of a collection point
比如呕吐物，口水以及其它各种排泄物
for vomit and sputum and other bodily secretions.
在这些防滑的橡胶地板上，你能看见设计了许多深槽
So this floor, rubberised cork for grip, with drainage channels,
这些就是排污通道
so that the blood runs out.
车上有三个进出门和两个上下楼梯
There are three doorways and two staircases
这样小青年们就能快速地窜上去了
so that desperate teenagers can get upstairs as quickly as possible.
车内还配备了16台监控摄像头
There are 16 CCTV security cameras on board,
并且这些座椅，是受到老款巴士的影响
and this upholster,which is inspired by that used
而设计的，所以看起来更加亲切，坐上去也同以前一样舒服
on the original Routemaster, so that we find it comforting and familiar.
最后还有这个，我最喜欢的设计
And then there's this,which I particularly like.
这块屏幕能告诉你上层的座位
This screen tells you when you get on the bus
是否满员
whether or not the top deck is full,
所以二层满员的时候你不用白白跑上去再跑下来
so you don't waste your life going up and down the stairs.
说到操控性
Now, handling.
在这样的道路上驾驶一辆超级跑车，你会吓得手心出汗
On a road like this, in a supercar,you'd be clammy-handed
但是在这辆车上，我很轻松
and frightened,but in my bus, I was very relaxed.
♪我在遥望，月亮之上...♪
♪ Da-da, da-da-da... ♪
这引起了我的思考。如果把这辆车开上赛道会怎样？
And this got me thinking. How would the bus cope with a track day?
现在各位观众估计在猜测我们是不是又要来一场疯狂的
Now you might think we're just being deliberately silly
公交碰碰车比赛之类的玩意，但是，是这样吗？
in a Top Gear, sort of, way,but are we?
因为NBFL有许多赛车的特点
Because the NBFL has a lot of features that you'd want in a track day car.
比如它是后置引擎，就像保时捷911一样，它是后轮驱动
It's rear-engined, like a Porsche 911, it's rear wheel drive.
它有巨大的轮胎。当我们来到车的前端
It has massive tyres. And then if we move down to the front...
我们有着极度开阔的视野，一个非常
we find excellent all-round visibility, a lofty,
有利于驾驶的位置
commanding driving position
这能让我在任何弯道中都极具竞争力
that will give me a good view of all the bends.
不幸的是，虽然看上去很适合赛道
Unfortunately, while that sounded good in the paddock,
但还是有些问题的
there were some issues.
六点钟方向
Bandits on my six.
小混混！
Yobbo!
在直线上，它慢得令人发指
On the straights, for instance,it was woefully slow.
跑快点啊！
More speed!
但在弯道里，你能开的和普通巴士司机一样霸道
But in the corners, you could at least behave like a bus driver.
我把保时捷挡在线路之外
I've shut the door on the Porsche.
你那小身板在这里没用！
Your Oyster card is about to expire!
冲线！
And across the line!
谢谢
Thank you.
我从没在赛道上跑得这么欢
I have never enjoyed my time on a race track as much as that.
实际上，我在这车里的一整天都很享受。当然也有些缺点
In fact, I enjoyed my whole day with the bus. There are a few drawbacks.
比如停车，油耗，倒车等等
Parking,fuel consumption, reversing,
但同样的问题也困扰着像布加迪威龙这样的超级跑车
but all that is true of the Bugatti Veyron, as well.
好的方面，这车很宽敞，很有个性
On the plus side,it's roomy, it's distinctive,
驾驶感也很出色
and it's extremely nice to drive.
所有这一切，都使它堪称一辆超级巴士
All in all,I think it would make a super car.
等等
Hang on.
等等。什么？
Hang on a minute. What?
你是不是五感尽失了？
Have you completely taken leave of your senses?
你说这家伙是这家伙的替代者？
Are you seriously proposing THIS as an alternative to THIS?
不，这么看，哈蒙德，听我说。艾伦·休格(英国的亿万富翁),他是个富豪
No, look, Hammond, let me explain.Lord Sir Sugar, he is a wealthy man,
但他对0-60英里加速两秒以内的事情没兴趣，对吧？
but he's not interested in doing nought to 60 in two seconds, is he?
如果他有一辆这车，他就能招待好他的小伙伴们
If he had one of these,he could take all his mates, well,
如果他有小伙伴的话，并且度过愉快的一天
if he's got any,and have a lovely day out.
这很难证实，对吧？
It's hardly practical, is it?
不，哈蒙德，我认为梅说明了一件事。噢，看在上帝的份上...
No, Hammond, I think he's onto something. Oh, for God's sake...
不，不，如果你想要一辆雷克萨斯LFA
No, no, because if you wanted a Lexus LFA,
但你又是一个计划生育政策的反对者
but you'd had a papal attitude to birth control -
换言之你有很多孩子 - 这就是你的不二选择
a lot of children - this is ideal.
没错。你也不用自己开车
Exactly right.And you don't have to drive,
你能找个人为你开车
you could get somebody to drive it for you.
我们通常把这人叫做，我不知道该怎么说，公交司机。
You could call him the,I don't know, the bus driver.
噢，搞什么名堂！等等，这个主意怎么样？
Oh, for crying out loud!Hang on, how's this for an idea?
你等地方政府买下这车
You get the local authority to buy the bus
然后你就可以乘坐它了,你唯一要做的只是每次上车刷卡而已
and then you can just use it now and then in return for a small fee.
不，詹姆斯，那就变成共产主义了
No, James, that would be communism.
总之，现在又到了我们的明星驾驶廉价车环节
Anyway, it's time now to put a star in our reasonably-priced car.
今晚我的嘉宾是一个住在英国的澳洲人
Now, my guest tonight is an Australian who lives in Britain,
但不寻常的是，他不在酒吧工作
but, unusually,he doesn't work in a pub.
相反,他的工作是在
Instead, he works in the marketing department
一家大型能量饮料制造公司的营销部门，并且刚刚提交了辞职信
of a large energy drinks company and he's just handed his notice in.
女士们先生们，欢迎马克韦伯
Ladies and gentlemen,please welcome Mark Webber.
马克韦伯！
Mark Webber!
你好吗？
How are you?
请坐。请坐
Have a seat. Have a seat.
最受欢迎的人物，我说过，在F1围场内
One of the most popular figures,I say, in Formula 1.
我们有如此多的相似处
Now, we have so much in common.
我们有相同的体重，我了解的。你们笑啥？
We have the same body fat index,I know that. Why are you laughing?
一模一样。但最主要的是我们有共同之处
Exactly the same. But the main thing we have in common,
除了相同的体重
apart from the same body fat index,
还有爱好骑单车
is cycling.
我现在是个骑自行车的人
I'm now a cyclist.
我听说这是你的新爱好
I hear it's a new passion for you.
而你，当然，所有人都知道你是个单车运动员
And you, of course,are well-known as a cyclist.
你参加了很多比赛。我今年也参加了几次比赛
You do a lot of competing. I've done a little bit over the years.
有人说你是最合适的车手
Somebody said you are the fittest driver.
我有合适的体型。我认为所有的人都适合。
I'm in reasonable shape.I think all the guys are fit now.
如果你是最合适的F1车手
If you're the fittest Formula 1 driver,
你就是这个世界上所有运动的最合适运动员
you've got to be one of the fittest athletes.
如果我们做了很多不同的尝试,我想,是这么回事
If we did lots and lots of different challenges, I think, yeah.
那样真不错。你可以试试不同的运动
That would be good.Let's get you all playing all the different sports.
你玩足球吗？欧洲足球还是你们澳洲那种愚蠢的足球？
Do you play football?Ours or your silly football?
不要聊狮子巡回赛（橄榄球赛事，四年一届）
We won't get onto the Lions and Australia.
说点别的
We'll leave that well alone.
这里有了解的人。有人知道你说的是什么
Somebody's here. Somebody understands what you're on about.
狮子队和小袋鼠队，我们很喜欢这两支队伍
Lions and Wallabies,we really enjoyed that.
还有灰烬杯（灰烬杯板球赛，英国和澳洲之间的世界板球顶级赛事）
And the Ashes.
你一定很喜欢住在这里的这最后几年
You must have really enjoyed living here these last few years.
我认为上届灰烬杯很精彩
I thought the previous Ashes was quite a good series.
我的意思是,英国队的南非裔球员表现的很好
I mean, all the South Africans played well for you guys.
你骑车的总里程数有多少了？骑车？
So how much mileage have you done on the bike? On the bike?
我已经骑了...三
I've done... three.
3英里（4.8公里）
Three miles.
我对单车运动有一点要说明，这是个，这么说吧
One thing I will say about cycling is, it is, well,
这是一项很危险的运动
it's pretty dangerous.
这么多年来，你也有过很多次赛道事故，是这样吧
Over the years, you've had a number of car accidents, let's be honest.
如果你参加比赛，你就会遇上撞车
If you race cars, you'll crash cars.
我们有张事故照片。是勒芒24小时耐力赛的一次事故
We've got a photograph of a crash.I believe it was at Le Mans.
一张静态照片。没错，这就是你以前驾驶的奔驰赛车
A still photo.Yeah, this is you in a Mercedes.
我刚说赛车事故，这看起来实际上是场空难。当时怎么回事？
I say car crash, that is a plane crash going on. How did that happen?
实际上，在那条赛道上，90年代末期，那些赛车安全性很糟糕
Actually, in that era, the late 90s,the cars were super unsafe,
所以很多赛车都飞起来过。这是常事
so a lot of cars were flying.Just the regulations.
所以当时你在那辆车里，想些什么...?
So you're sitting in there,thinking...?
我当时想，显然我失去控制了
I'm thinking,obviously I'm now out of control.
至于你信不信，我反正信了，当时我就是失去控制了
Believe it or not,I'm now out of control.
就像飚车的年轻人那样，那时我已经失去了对车的控制
As arrogant as us boys are,I have now lost control of that car.
就是这么回事。你当时还踩着刹车吗？
That's gone. Do you find yourself in a situation like that braking?
刹车灯还亮着，大概，没错
The brakelights will still be on, probably, yes.
为什么还不减速？
"Why isn't it slowing down?"
之后还有一次，当然，是在F1里的那次碰撞
And then, of course, that was the big Formula 1 airborne one.
是在瓦伦西亚吗？是的。那是一次很严重的撞车
Was that Valencia? Yeah.It was quite a big crash.
我们有段录像
We've got the footage here,
给各位重温一下韦伯的那段经历，你人生中最刺激的一刻，是的
just to remind everybody of Mark,one of your finest hours, really.
又看了一遍，我觉得...
Again, I find myself...
当时那一瞬间你大脑里都在想些什么
What does go through your mind apart from,
哇噢，那就像坐游乐场里的过山车一样？
"Wow, it's like a fairground ride"?
你只是需要离莲花赛车远一点，伙计，这就是你需要做的
You've just got to stay away from Lotuses mate,that's the long and short of it.
通过这两场事故
The thing about both of those accidents,
我认为首先，你一定受到了一点...
I think the first one,you suffered a little bit of...
我有些脑震荡，脖子也有点伤
I had some concussion, neck problems.
是那次吗，那次F1的撞车？我很走运
That one, though, the one in the Formula 1 car? I was lucky.
我踩断了制动踏板,实际上。这就是当时发生的事情
I snapped the brake pedal,actually. So that was about it.
通常我们不在那里踩刹车
Which is unusual to do from that side.
需要很大的力量，和勇气
A lot of power required, adrenaline.
你实际上还踩坏了你的...？断了。突然断裂
You actually broke it with your own...? Snapped it. Just popped it.
什么，你用脚踩断了刹车？是的
What, just with the force of your own foot? Exactly.
所以你从这两场事故中一路走来，令人印象深刻
So you walk away from both those accidents, which is remarkable,
2008年开始你还参加自行车比赛
and yet you go cycling in 2008,
撞到一辆日产都灵，我记得。那辆日产赢了，伙计，日产赢了
bump into a Nissan Torino,I believe. It won, mate, it won.
日产赢了。你撞断了你的腿？
It won. And you broke your leg?
是的。和肩膀...
Yeah. Shoulder...
因为这是一个教育孩子们的好案例
Because this is what I think we need to impress upon children watching.
不要骑自行车。因为它们很危险
Don't get a bicycle.Because they're dangerous.
现在，很显然，就像我们在介绍中说的那样，你已经确认不再参加明年的F1比赛
Now obviously, you've, as we said in the introduction, handed notice in.
为什么？你要去哪？你将要做些什么？
Why? Where are you going?What you going to do?
如今这个时间正适合我，伙计
Timing's right for me, mate.
对于已经参加14年F1比赛的我来说，是时候调整一下了
Bit of a break from what I've been doing for the last 14 years.
我明年就去保时捷车队跑勒芒了，事实上
So I'm going to race with Porsche, actually.
我知道你一直很喜欢保时捷，对吧？
I know you love Porsches, don't you?
911是部好车！
The 911 is such an interesting car!
不，让我疑虑的是，你真觉得现在是你离开F1的最佳时机吗？
No, cos what worries me,do you think you're getting out at the right time of Formula 1?
如今F1有了不稳定的轮胎
Now that we've got the tyres going off like they do,
这是不是使得比赛变得乏味了？
is that getting a bit wearisome?
你坐进赛车，赛车很棒，你也了解赛道
You're in the car, the car's going well, you know the track,
你在最佳的状态，并且你知道如果你全力驾驶的话
you're in the groove and you know that if you push hard,
你的轮胎会快速衰竭这样你就赢不了比赛了
your tyres will simply wear out and you can't win.
这很不同，伙计，和以前比较起来
It is very different, mate,from how it used to be.
但现实就是如此，所以我们要不断学习并掌握它
But that's the way it is, we've got to learn and get on with it.
你在F1里要学会进步
But you've got to be able to push.In Formula 1,
全心全意地投入其中.就应该这样
it's about us boys absolutely on the limits all the time. It should be.
明年F1规则会有大改变
There's a big regulation change next year.
赛车会变得更加省油。1.6升排量的引擎？
We're going to have to save fuel.1.6 litre engines?
我想说我的福特科蒂娜也是1.6升的排气量
I mean, my Ford Cortina had a 1.6 litre engine.
所以你会想念你的队友吗？
So are you going to miss your team-mate?
我会不会想念维特尔？
Am I going to miss Seb?
大概不会太想他，不会
Probably not a huge amount, no.
在一个竞争的环境里，总有一点点不和谐的气氛
In a competitive environment, there's always going to be a bit of needle.
我们之间有很多恩怨，显然，但那都是过去时了
There's a lot of history between us two, obviously, that's gone before.
是不是从今年马来西亚站开始他就变得不太听话了？
Did it start in Malaysia when he suddenly lost the ability to hear?
车队对他说“不要超过韦伯”
It was basically "Don't overtake Mark",
他听到了除了“不要”之外的每一个字
and then he heard everything apart from the "don't".
我想说，你是个澳洲人。你是否曾经有过一种冲动想要...?
I mean, you're an Aussie.Have you never felt tempted to...?
这是为了报我那一箭之仇
"This is for Gallipoli, blam!"
很多人都说是的。我有些不安了
A lot of people are saying yes.I'm a bit concerned.
我老爸曾经教导我“不要欺负小朋友”，所以...
My dad always says,"You shouldn't hit boys, mate", so...
说得好
Good one.
现在你回到我们的节目是为了刷新上次的记录
Now you're here for the second time, in fact.
不同的演播室，所有的东西都不同了
Different studio,everything's a bit different.
今天有点紧张。你去过老演播室？是的
I was a bit nervous today.Were you in the old studio? Yeah.
你看上去比原来老了一半
You actually looked half-decent back then.
我要退休了，我真的要退休了
I've gone, I've absolutely gone.
我头发也白了，伙计。你也白了
I've got grey, too, mate.You've got grey.
理查德哈蒙德头发没白
Richard Hammond hasn't gone grey.
这真奇怪。难以置信
It's really weird.That's incredible.
我都不知道他怎么保养的
I don't know how he's keeping it at bay.
闲话少叙，让我们看看你的赛道表现
Anyway, let's find out how you got on on your laps.
你以前来过一次，说实话...
You came here once before and, let's be honest...
那次下着大雨，我跑的一团糟
It was chucking it down and I was nowhere.
你上次成绩是1分47秒，但那次雨真的很大
You were 1.47, but it was the wettest day in human history.
但这次没有下雨。赛道情况很不错
Well, today was not raining.Very good conditions.
赛道相当理想，那正是铃木利亚纳最适宜的温度
Good conditions, the right temperatures for a Suzuki Liana.
谁想看看韦伯的单圈？
Who'd like to have a look at this lap?
是的！
Yeah!
让我们看看。放录像，看看韦伯跑的怎么样
Let's have a look. Come on, Mark.Let's have a look at the lap.
好的，出发了。我要超过你们
Righto, here we go.Coming to get you.
刘易斯和塞巴斯蒂安
Lewis and Sebastian.
好的，他们俩是标杆成绩。来到第一弯
Right, those are the two targets.The first corner.
走线很漂亮也很宽。你的走线很有意思
Nice and wide on the way. And it is interesting how you lot all do that.
看看利亚纳，多么棒的一辆车
Look at the Liana, what a machine.
F1车手都怎么回事？
What is it with Formula 1 drivers?
Kimi上次跑到这里还在欣赏那边的直升飞机
Kimi was looking at the helicopters and planes
现在你居然整理仪容。你要去哪？
and now you're adjusting your clothing. Where are you going?
集中注意力。这方向盘真是太灵敏了
Pay attention.The steering's very responsive.
这拉风的特性会帮助你取得好成绩。好的，锤子弯
That'll help with your time.Right, Hammerhead.
走线紧凑些，紧凑些。真可怕，锤子弯
Keep it tight, keep it in.It's horrible, Hammerhead.
这走的是什么路线啊？
What's that?
你在这段会有很强的抓地力。这里铺了新的沥青
You keep the grip up.There's new asphalt there.
这里抓地力很棒，真的非常棒
It's good grip on that,really good grip.
不要在这里减速
Don't scrub any speed through these fast ones.
轻柔的转向，来了
Turning lightly, here we go.
来了，上次休杰克曼就是这样。哦嚯！
Here we are,the Hugh Jackman. Ooh!
切弯漂亮
Cutting it nicely.
你是怎么保持的？看看这个弯的速度多快啊！
How do you carry? Look how much speed you've got going into that!
很震撼。不错，但有点跳动，实际上
That's impressive.Well, bound to be, really.
这里，不，我不会在这里减档
And here, no, I wouldn't have changed down there
但是一圈完毕，冲线了
but there we are, across the line.
我刚才对你说“我不会在这里减档”
I just said "I wouldn't have changed down there" to YOU!
最后一个弯你用二档过的？是的
Second gear in the last corner,second? Yeah.
我在Gambon弯用三档。你呢？
I use third in Gambon. Do you?
好吧，准确来说这一切都结束了，所以现在讨论也没什么意义
Well, on the basis that it's the end, so it doesn't really matter
如果你那时换档。之后会没有动力传递给三档
if you roll it or burst.There's no weight transfer in third.
我希望把驱动力都传递给前轮。重心转移给前轮？
I want to get the weight on the front tyre. The weight on the front?
你看，我点刹了。点刹？带了一点点
You see, I trail break.Trail breaking? A little bit.
但对于克服惯性还是不够。只是让车能更好入弯
Still not enough inertia.It just gets the weight of the nose.
等下我会给你好好上一课。至少我能做到的事情
I'll give you some lessons after.The least I can do.
不管怎样，你猜你会排在哪？
Anyway, where do you think?
显然，你说了你是要打败维特尔和汉密尔顿的
Obviously, you said you were going for Sebastian and Lewis,
谁在最顶端。谁就是我的目标
who are right up at the top.That was the goal.
好吧，我有你的成绩。我要看看。等等
Well, I've got the time here. I shall have a look. Hang on a minute.
我很喜欢你们这群F1车手，事实上
I love the way that Formula 1 drivers, actually,
你看起来对此相当期待。这真是相当有趣
it's like you really care about this. Cos it is quite funny.
我还记得巴里切罗当时知道他是最快的人之后那种兴奋的表情
I mean Rubens was really dead chuffed when he was fastest.
他跑出去到处散发T恤衫，上面写着“我就是击败Stig的...”
He was running around handing out,"I am the beat..."
他确实那么干了，他也给了我一件
He was, he gave me one.
不论如何，马克韦伯...
Anyway, Mark Webber...
你的成绩。好吧，我首先要宣布一个坏消息
You did it. Well, I'm going to start with the bad news.
真的吗？是的，你不是最快的
Really? Yeah. You're not fastest.
所以，当我说出那个成绩的时候，关键就在于
So, really, once we got that one out the way, the big question is,
这个德国人
ze German.
你是否击败了这个做出1分44秒成绩的德国人？
Did you beat ze German,who did a 1.44 dead?
前三差距很小。都离1分44秒很近
It's quite tight between those three.It is very tight in the 1.44s.
真的很接近。所以马克韦伯，你的成绩是1分...
It's all very tight.So, Mark Webber, you did 1...
40...
接下来这个数字是关键
The next number's important.
3.噢！
Three. Ooh!
你击败了维特尔
You beat Seb.
只落后汉密尔顿0.2秒
Only .2 off Lewis.
这真是...
That...
我估计到会这样
I reckon that did it.
我估计到你会采纳我给你的建议
I reckon if you'd just taken my advice
最后一个弯要用三档
about third at the final corner.
事实上，你没有比汉密尔顿更快，但你也没戴耳钉
The thing is, you're not faster than Lewis but you don't have an earring.
这样。戴耳钉会慢0.3秒，是吧？
OK. That's worth 3/10, isn't it?
0.3秒，是的，戴耳钉
It's got to be 3/10,yeah, with his earring.
但你终于用同一辆车击败了维特尔
But you have beaten Sebastian Vettel in the same car.
女士们先生们，马克韦伯！
Ladies and gentlemen, Mark Webber!
真不错
Tremendous.
好的，正如这些年我们知道的那样
Now, for years we've known
捷豹正在研发一款新的小型运动跑车
that Jaguar was working on a new small sports car.
我们知道它将被称作F-type
We've known that it's going to be called the F-type
我们对它抱有各种美好的幻想
and we had a pretty good idea of what it would be like.
是的，我们知道这将是一辆安静，舒适
Yeah, we knew that it was going to be quiet and comfortable
内敛的小车，并且内饰充满了传统风格的皮饰
and restrained and that the interior would be full of traditional leather
木头以及苔藓
and wood and moss.
我们猜的对吗？
So were we right?
简而言之，不对
In short, no.
我们猜错了
We were not right.
它是一部限制级作品，一辆凶猛的怪兽
It's an X-rated,hardcore monster...
为精神错乱晚期人士量身打造
for the terminally unhinged.
它有如此宽广的排气声浪
It's got such a wide range of intoxicating noises.
当你升档时，它就像头河马
When you change up,it snorts like a hippo.
当你踩下油门，它就开始演奏
And when you put your foot down, it bellows.
当你再次减挡时...
And when you take it off again...
排气声
RUMBLING
你听过这样的排气声浪吗？
Have you heard a soundtrack like that?
这声浪仿佛来自60年代！
That is the sound of the '60s right there!
如果你按下这个小按钮
And if you push this little button here,
你就启动了运动排气系统，这会让它变得更响亮
you engage the sports exhaust system, which makes it even louder.
它不会咆哮也不会咬人
It's not all bark and no bite, either.
机械增压的3.0升V6引擎拥有
The 3L V6 engine is supercharged
375马力的强劲动力
and delivers 375 fire-spitting horse powers.
0-60英里加速时间4.8秒
It does 0-60 in 4.8 seconds.
极速171英里每小时（275公里）
Top speed, 171.
这辆车甚至还不是捷豹最快的版本
And this isn't even the fast version.
如果你需要，捷豹会为你换成488匹马力的V8引擎
If you want,Jaguar will sell you a 488hp V8.
虽然我不会对此感到不满
I wouldn't bother, though,
因为当我驾驶这辆车的时候，我就一直这么认为
because at no point while I've been driving this, have I thought,
“是的，但我希望它要是能更刺激一点就好了”
"Yeah, but I wish it was a bit more exciting."
现在，你可能会猜想这样一辆又吵又粗暴的车
Now, you would imagine that a car this loud and this brutal
会是一辆很简陋粗糙的作品
would be as luxurious as a Methodist's coal house.
但是，你错了
But, no.
车顶能在你以30英里（48公里）
The roof can be raised or lowered,
时速行驶时自由打开和关闭
even when you're going 30 miles an hour.
按钮全部是镀铜材质
The switches are bronzed.
座椅也是电动可调的
The seats are electric.
你还能调节车内的氛围灯光颜色
And you can choose what shade of mood lighting you'd like.
内饰，做得很精致
The interior, then,is nicely thought out,
但是这和它的外观没有啥联系
but it is nothing compared to the exterior.
我认为这是我见过的最漂亮的车型
I think this is one of the best-looking cars ever made.
所以，这是辆漂亮的，疯狂的，粗鲁的，很吵的车
So, it's beautiful and mad and thrilling and loud.
对此还有很多要说的
And there's more.
如今许多车给人感觉就像是笔记本电脑，但这辆车不是
A lot of cars these days feel like laptops, but this doesn't.
是的，这辆车你也能进入电脑
Yes, you can go into the computer
选择变速箱和引擎的模式
and alter the characteristics of the gearbox and the engine
以及调节转向和悬挂，但另一方面
and the steering and suspension, but that said,
这车没有双离合器
there's no double clutch gearbox.
有的仅是一台平顺的八速自动变速器
It's just a smooth,eight-speed auto.
这里也没有6档牵引力控制系统
There's no six-way traction control,
没有复杂的折叠硬顶
there's no complicated folding metal roof.
它比你想象的还要简单
It's much simpler than that.
前置引擎，后轮驱动
Engine at the front,drive to the rear
再加上一个坐在里面的驾驶员
and a big, smiling piece of meat in the middle.
底盘很出色，刹车也很出色，转向系统也同样出色
The chassis is epic, and so are the brakes, and so's the steering.
你有很大的抓地力
And you've got tons of locks,
所以当你超过操控极限时，它能很轻易的把你救回来
so if you do get it out of shape,it's easy to get it back again.
在许多方面，它把我的思绪带回了宝马M3并且...
In many ways, it puts me in mind of a BMW M3 and that is...
这是个非常高的评价
That is high praise.
除了它不是一辆宝马之外
Except, it's not a BMW.
这是辆捷豹
It's a Jag.
我真希望我能就此结束介绍这车，但不幸的是
And I wish I could end it there,but, unfortunately,
还有两件事需要补充一下
there are one or two issues that need mentioning.
我刚刚完成了我的一周大采购
I've just done my weekly shop.
我买了一些果酱...
I bought some jam...
一杯牛奶...
some milk...
一袋糖...
some sugar...
还有一些黄油
and some butter.
遗憾的是，我没办法再多买点东西了
Sadly, I wasn't able to buy any more than that,
因为如果你给你的捷豹配备了一个备胎的话
because if you buy your Jag with a spare wheel,
这将是你后备箱的样子
this is what the boot looks like.
捷豹怎么能在开了无数会议之后认为这是能被接受的设计？
How could they have a meeting and decide that THAT was acceptable?
这真是蠢透了！
It's just madness!
还有一点 - 那就是价格
And there's another problem - the price.
我曾猜想V6版本的车大概会卖5万英镑（47万人民币）
I was expecting the V6 version to cost around £50,000.
但实际上，它卖到了几乎68000英镑（63.9万人民币）
But actually, it's almost £68,000.
而V8版本的价格更是开到了让人泪奔的80000英镑（75.1万人民币）
And the V8 is an eye-watering £80,000.
但更大的问题，是在郊外公路上的驾乘感
But the biggest problem,by a country mile, is the ride.
这条路看起来似乎很平坦
This road appears to be completely smooth,
但实际上我的感觉是正行驶在一条...
but it feels like I'm driving...
不，我不像是在开车，我感觉更像是在滑旱冰
No, not driving,it feels like I'm roller-skating,
穿着一双钢制滑轮的旱冰鞋
over a piece of corrugated iron.
这感觉...呃！
It's just... urgh!
当你在小镇上开的慢一点时会感觉更糟
And it's even worse when you go slowly in a town.
那简直是无法忍受的颠簸
That's just unbearably harsh.
这种调校完全没必要
And there's no need for it.
当你有一个这么好的底盘，你根本没必要把悬挂调校得这么生硬
When you've got a chassis this good,you don't need hard suspension.
他们究竟是怎么想的？！
What were they thinking of?!
可喜的是，不管怎样，当你开的越快，你的感觉就越好
Happily, however, the ride does get better the faster you go.
这就是说，有一个解决该问题的办法
Which means, there is a way round the problem.
不要开得太慢
Don't drive slowly.
开的越快越好
Drive fast.
实话实说，在一辆这么漂亮的车里
Let's be honest,in a car that looks this good
声浪听起来也如此美妙，驾驶起来如此出色
and sounds this fantastic,and goes this well,
没啥可抱怨的
that's no hardship.
一点抱怨都没有
That is no hardship, at all.
又一辆适合在赫特福德郡驾驶的好车
Another amazing road in Hertfordshire.
你们应该经常去那驾驶
You should come there more often.
无论如何，捷豹，大家都知道，如今是一家印度公司
Anyway, Jaguar, as I'm sure you know, is now an Indian company,
但车辆的生产工作依旧在英国进行
but the cars are still made in Britain.
同样的现状，一开始介绍的路虎也是如此
And so are the Range Rovers that we were talking about earlier,
詹姆斯介绍的那辆巴士也是如此
and so is the bus that James thinks as a car.
这就让我们开始思考
And that got us thinking.
我们一直被灌输这样的理论
We're always been told
英国的制造业早已消亡
that Britain's manufacturing industry is dead,
我们不再制造任何东西
that we don't make stuff any more,
所以我们自然也不再制造汽车
and that we certainly don't make vehicles.
但是，真是这样吗？
But, do we?
好的，其实并不是这样，显然
Well, WE do, obviously.
我们制造了这台先进的混合动力汽车，
We made this pioneering hybrid electric car, using technology
如今这项技术风靡全球
that is now copied globally.
我们也制造了这台伟大的气垫车
And we made the magnificent Hovervan,
一台无与伦比的强悍机器
a machine of unparalleled capabilities,
质量无比可靠，使用中从未失败
many of which were not faked in any way, at all.
之后是一流的P45
And then there was the superb P45.
其实很烂
Which was terrible.
好吧，确实出过一两次小问题
Well, it had one or two issues.
是啊，都是致命的
Yeah, it was lethal.
好吧，但致命的只有一次而已
Yeah, being lethal was one of the issues.
但它是纯正的英国制造
But it was British built.
所以我们就开始思考，还有什么是我们英国制造的？
And we were wondering, what else is?
因此，在本次20季的最后一集节目里
And so, for the finale of the last programme of the series,
我觉得我们应该找出答案
we thought we should find out.
这就是大多数人对英国汽车工厂的印象
This is most people's idea of a British car factory.
一座1970年代就已经关闭的，被人遗忘的废墟
A ruin that closed down after some long-forgotten strike in the 1970s.
但事实证明，实际上
But it turns out that, actually,
还有很多超出你想象的英国汽车工厂正在进行生产
there's rather more going on than you might think.
如今，在英国的某些地方
Today, a new car rolls off a production line
每隔20秒就有一辆新车下线
somewhere in Britain every 20 seconds.
本田在史云顿建有工厂
Honda has a factory in Swindon,
那里有2700名工人生产
where 2,700 people are employed
思域，爵士，以及CRV等车型
to make the Civic,the Jazz, and the CRV.
丰田在德比郡建有工厂
Toyota makes cars in Derbyshire.
生产的汽车用于出口日本
Cars, which are then exported to Japan.
接下来是日产的工厂
And then there's the Nissan plant
建在英国东北部
in the Northeast.
去年，这座工厂生产的汽车数量
Last year,this one factory made more cars
比全意大利汽车厂生产的汽车总量还要多
than the whole of the Italian motor industry put together.
而这些，还不是我们制造的所有汽车
And it's not just whole cars we make, either.
去年，福特在全球卖出的每三辆汽车中
Last year, one in three Fords sold globally
就有一辆车的引擎出自威尔士或者艾塞克斯的工厂
had an engine made either in Wales or here in Essex.
不是仅此而已
And there's more.
接下来，我们来到了劳斯莱斯在苏塞克斯郡的工厂
And then, we arrive at the Rolls-Royce plant in Sussex,
这里，是的，许多部件都是来自德国
where, yes, many of the components are shipped over from Germany.
但是将它们组装起来的工作是在这里完成的
But the job of putting them all together is done here.
因为英国是唯一一个能把这些座椅真皮面料
Because Britain is the only country that appreciates
缝合的天衣无缝的国家
it's better to trim the seats with hide from bulls,
原因就在于牛在怀孕的时期皮质会产生妊娠纹
because cows get stretch marks when they're pregnant.
之后你还需要这些处理木料的技术工人
Then you have the people doing the wood.
他们都被称作，大师
Grandmasters, they're called.
在油漆车间，每辆车都要消耗掉45公斤的涂料
And the paint shop, where 45 kilos of paint is applied to each car.
然后，是这个环节
And then, there's this chap.
他的工作就是画上这些优美的线条
It's his job to apply the coach lines
完成最后对成品的装饰工作...
and embellishments to the finished product...
纯手工制作
by hand.
你在现代工厂里是找不到他的这些装备的
You won't find his equivalent in a Hyundai factory.
他把他的工作当成是一种休闲活动
He learned his trade as a pub sign writer.
据说他有一双全世界最稳的手
It's said he has the steadiest hand in the world.
然后，就要说到汽车赛事
Then, there's motor racing.
全世界，总共只有11支一级方程式车队
In the whole world,there are 11 Formula 1 teams.
8支的总部在英国
Eight are based in Britain
而其中7支车队的总部在我现在站在的这座位于牛津郡的山头上就能被看见
and seven can be seen from the top of this one hill in Oxfordshire.
那里，是威廉姆斯的总部
Over there, you have Williams.
那里是考斯沃斯的总部，那里是莲花和卡特汉姆车队总部
Up there in the Cotswolds,there's Lotus and Caterham.
接下去，再往更远的地方
Then, moving further along,
是印度力量和马鲁西亚的车队总部
we have Force India, Marussia,
还有红牛车队和奔驰车队
Red Bull and Mercedes.
英国对于汽车运动的贡献是非凡的
Britain's contribution to motorsport is extraordinary.
所有的印地赛车
All IndyCar races,
自从2009年以来的每辆达喀尔赛车
every Dakar winner since 2009,
今年勒芒LMP1组全部56辆赛车中的35辆赛车
35 of the 56 starters at this year's Le Mans,
包括冠军车队
including the car that won it.
还有马鲁西亚F1车队，帕加尼风神
The Marussia Formula 1 car,and the Pagani Huayra.
所有这些车的变速箱都来自于这座
All of them have gearboxes made in that factory
位于伯克郡工业区的小工厂
on this little industrial estate in Berkshire.
全球75%的汽车工业革新技术和升级
A whopping 75% of all research and development
都是在英国完成的
done in global motorsport is British.
英国制造的离合器
British clutch.
英国的制造的混合动力系统
British hybrid system.
英国制造的电控单元
British ECUs.
不只是我们自吹自擂，“噢，你看！我们是不是很聪明？”
And it's not just us saying,"Ooh, look! Aren't we clever?"
全世界都喜欢我们生产的产品
The rest of the world likes what we're doing these days.
在过去的7年里有超过5次
For five out of the last seven years,
阿斯顿马丁被评为“全球最酷的汽车品牌”
Aston Martin has been voted "coolest brand in the world".
并且，路虎揽胜也获得了一长串的全球获奖名单
And then, there's the list of global celebrities who drive a Range Rover.
现在把眼光从轿车领域转向重型机械
Time now to move away from the cars and into the heavy engineering.
从这张世界地图上看，所有红色区域的国家都使用
On this map of the world,all the countries shaded in red
英国制造的军用装甲车
use military vehicles made in Britain.
所有绿色区域的国家
All the countries shaded green
都使用英国制造的卡车运输货物
use British-made lorries to move stuff around.
所有黄色区域的国家
In all the countries shaded yellow,
都至少有一辆JCB工程机械用来建造建筑物
there's at least one JCB helping to build something.
虽然接下来这一幅地图和重型机械没啥关系
And while it's not exactly heavy engineering,
所有褐色区域的国家都收看英国制作的汽车节目
all the countries shaded brown watch British-made motoring shows.
既然认清了我们英国确实也制造了很多伟大的车辆
Having established we do make quite a lot of stuff in Britain,
于是我们决定统计一下英国究竟制造了多少
we decided to find out just how much.
因此我们发起了一个雄心勃勃的计划
So we hatched an ambitious plan.
我们向所有车辆制造商发出了邀请
We called all the companies that make motorised vehicles
并向他们询问“能把你们生产的车辆
and said to them, "Could you bring whatever it is you make
开到伦敦来做个展示吗？”
"to a gathering in London?"
这其中摩根遇到一点小麻烦
A little bit of a problem with Morgan,
因为他们不知道伦敦是什么地方
who didn't know what London was,
但最终，每家工厂都给出了积极的响应
but eventually,everybody responded magnificently.
杰瑞米，理查德，和我挑选了三辆不同型号的
Jeremy, Richard, and I are taking three different versions
F-Type前往伦敦
of the new F-Type to London.
例如，我挑选了一辆V6车型...
I, for example, have the V6...
哇噢！那些是凯旋摩托车
Whoa! That's the Triumph bikes.
真不错！
Tremendous!
与此同时，在遥远的乡村...
Meanwhile,deep in the countryside...
噢，瞧瞧那边！
Oh, look at that!
现在，看看谁来了！
And now, look what's coming!
是摩根家族。加油，伙计们！
It's the Morgans. Carry on, chaps!
比其他人更晚一些
Much later than everyone else,
F1赛车们也启程前往伦敦
the Formula 1 cars began to leave for London.
在米尔顿凯恩斯（F1车队总部聚集区，银石赛道所在地），这景象真是蔚为壮观
Which, in Milton Keynes,was quite a sight.
雄壮的声浪
And quite a sound.
最终，前往伦敦的车队们
Eventually, the fleet of vehicles that had been made in Britain
开始向首都的目的地汇聚
began to arrive on the streets of the capital.
在跑得最慢的伙计们找到了地点之后...
And after the slowest had turned up...
我们坐进捷豹车
we climbed into our Jags
前往集合地点
and headed for the meeting point
去看看究竟聚集了多少车
to see how much stuff was there.
这感觉真的很特别，干这件事
This feels a bit special, this does.
当我们驶过白金汉宫
And it became even more special
以及林荫大道时
as we swung past Buckingham Palace
这感觉变得更加特殊
and onto The Mall.
这比我想象的还要多
There's more than I thought.
林荫大道这些年举办过很多庆典
The Mall has hosted many uplifting scenes over the years.
但是这里从没举办过这样的聚会
But it has never hosted anything quite like this before.
让我们惊叹不已的不仅是这壮观的场面
It wasn't just the sheer volume that took our breath away.
更是这些种类繁多的差异性，这种宽宏的气势
It was the diversity, the breadth.
轿车，卡车，挖掘机，赛车
Cars, lorries, diggers, racers,
冰淇凌车，灵车
ice cream vans, hearses.
真是太壮观了
It was magnificent.
真是大手笔
It was huge.
我都不知道我们制造了这些自卸卡车
I didn't know we made those massive tipper trucks.
看看那车！
Look at that that thing!
拖拉机
A tractor.
完全没想到
I didn't think of that.
陆地最快纪录车！
Land speed record cars!
那是我测评过的巴士！看见了吗，伙计们？
There's my bus! All right, mate?
哦嚯，捷豹鹰E型！
Ooh, the Eagle!
如今很多人这么说
A lot of people say that, today,
英国不过是一个世界银行，或者一个精品商店，或者一个已经没落的昔日霸主
Britain is nothing more than a bank,or a boutique, or a busted flush,
但是看看我身后停着的这些令人惊叹的展示车...
but looking at that staggering collection back there...
我对他们的言论表示怀疑。
I'm not sure they're right.
晚安
Good night.
遗忘天下，个人翻译，如有错误，万望海涵
制作：遗忘天下 校订：遗忘天下 上传：遗忘天下  QQ号：529098103 欢迎车迷同学加好友
英文字幕来源MemoryOnSmells http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.